Deepak Shiv

Email: deepakshiv2009@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-8087044673

Total Experience

8+ Years in BI/DW

Qualification

MCA (Masters of Computer Application)

Work history

Pyramid Consulting Inc.

Jul 2021 – Present

InfoCepts Technologies

Mar 2015 – Jul 2021

Cognizant Technology Sol.

Oct 2012-Dec 2014

Expertise

- Informatica Powercenter
 - • • •
- Informatica Admin
- Data Modelling
- Oracle



Work Summary

- Informatica Architect
- Informatica Admin
- Informatica Developer

Summary and Accomplishments

- 8+ Years of of experience in Project Execution, ETL & Data Warehousing,
 Training & Development and Software Development
- Worked as Data Modeler and Informatica Architect for leading Real Estate and Entertainment company
- Prepared RFP (Request for Proposal) bidding proposal document to pitch in for new clients
- Have expertise in calculating ETL effort & estimation
- Trained 100+ laterals and freshers on Informatica PC

Technical Skills

ETL Tool Informatica Powercentre 10.4, SSIS

Data Modeling Normalized, De-normalized, Star, Snowflake

Schemas

Data Modelling Tool ERWIN

Business Intelligence Tools Tableau

Databases Oracle, SQL Server, Greenplum

Programming Languages VB.Net, Unix Shell scripting, Curl Script, Python

Scheduler JAMS

Operating Systems Windows 32bit / 64 bit, Linux

Ticketing tool ServiceNow

Project Profiles

Project Details

Leading Power Company

AMnO and Development *Dec 2017 – Jul 2021*

Role

Informatica Admin/Senior Informatica Developer

Project Description

The Company is an independent power producer founded in 2015. It owns 15,320 megawatts of power generating capacity with plants located in USA. Company's generation facilities include nuclear, coal fired, natural gas and hydro-electric power plants. The objective of the project is to help the BI team set up and efficiently manage their BI systems

Responsibilities

- Involved in all high-level discussion and gather business requirement
- Create ETL spec design document for developers
- Informatica installation, Migration and Outage handling, Code sync in all environment, Bouncing Activities
- Upgraded Informatica 9.6 to 10.1 & 10.1 to 10.4 using Sandbox based approach
- Have worked upon Informatica advanced transformation XML (Source Qualifier, Parser, Generator), SQL, Stored Procedure, Normalizer transformation
- Have worked upon Informatica integration with ServiceNow using HTTP
- Have done automation using Curl and Postman for downloading invoices
- Done POC for loading into Greenplum using Informatica Powerexchange

Project Details

Leading Entertainment Company

BI Operational Insight *May 2015 – Nov 2017*

Role

Data Modeler/ETL Architect/ Senior Informatica Developer

Project Description

It is one of the world's most valuable and admired real estate development companies in UAE. With proven competencies in property, shopping malls & retail and hospitality & leisure, company shapes new lifestyles with a focus on design excellence, build quality and timely delivery.

Responsibilities

- Requirement gathered for the new system
- Design complete Data Model for the system
- Created Staging and DWH environment
- Created High level ETL design document
- Involved in designing complex Informatica mappings
- Optimize ETL Process

Project Details

Cognizant Technology Solutions

Leading Health Care
Company, COMPASS
Oct 2012 – December 2014

Role

Informatica & Cognos Developer

Project Description

It is a multinational pharmaceutical company. The company has core businesses in pharmaceuticals, vaccines, consumer health, generics, eye care and animal health.

Responsibilities

- Worked on bug fix and new enhancement in COMPASS Application
- Environment monitoring to check whether the infrastructure is readily available
- Communicated with client and on-site coordinator, gather requirement for new CR's and enhancement
- Handled operational activity like giving update to Sr. Manager (Offshore and Onsite) regarding Remedy Tickets, Utilization Report, Metrics Reporting for different application